A Guide to the NASA Project Tapes, 1963-1966
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
NASA Project Tapes, 1963-1966
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2001-020
0.4 Cubic Feet; 1 box
This collection contains 16 reel to reel audio tapes of various NASA projects from 1963 through 1966. These tapes include news conferences from Kennedy Space Center and pertaining to Projects Gemini and Mercury, John Glenn, Gus Grissom, and other astronauts. These tapes also include some recordings of launchings and landings from these projects.
United States. National Aeronautical and Space Administration
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated to Special Collections in June 2001.
Scope and Content
This collection comprises 16 reel to reel audiotapes of various NASA projects and news conferences from the Kennedy Space Center from 1963 through 1966. The tapes pertain to Project Mercury and Project Gemini (3, 4, 5, 7, 9, and 11). Some tapes include audio of launching and landing from the projects. The crew members included from Project Mercury are John Glenn, Scott Carpenter, Walter M. Shirra, and L. Gordon Cooper, and the crew members from Project Gemini are Gus Grissom, James A. McDivitt, Edward H. White II, Eugene A. Cernan, Thomas P. Stafford, Pete Conrad, Gordon Cooper, Frank Borman, Jim Lovell, and John Young.
Arrangement
The collection is primaily arranged chronologically.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Archives of American Aerospace Exploration (AAAE); Science and Technology
Organizations:
United States. National Aeronautical and Space Administration
Contents List
- Audio Reel, Glenn #1 (Box 1, Reel 1)
- Audio Reel, Glenn #2, 1962-02-20 (Box 1, Reel 2)
- Audio Reel, Executive Board, Glenn #3, 1962-02-20 (Box 1, Reel 3)
- Audio Reel, 1962-04-07 (Box 1, Reel 4)
  Scope and Content
  Side 1 - Meeting
  Side 2 - John Noble (?)
- Audio Reel, 1962-05-24, 1969-06-08 (Box 1, Reel 5)
  Side 1 - Carpenter #2 landing
  Side 2 - Tennesse Ernie Ford
- Audio Reel, 1962-05-24 (Box 1, Reel 6)
  Side 1 - Second Astronaut, Carpenter #1
  Side 2 - Little over 3 hours of flight, thru 11:41am
- Audio Reel, 1962-10-03 (Box 1, Reel 7)
  Side 1 - Third Astronaut (Walter) Wally M. Shirra
  Side 2 - Walter M. Shirra - almost 1st half of 2nd side, Lots of Pete towards end
- Audio Reel, 1963-05-15 (Box 1, Reel 8)
  Side 1 - L. Gordon Cooper's take off
  Side 2 - Grace Carr
- Audio Reel, Kennedy, 1963-11-22 (Box 1, Reel 9)
- Audio Reel, Kennedy #2 (Box 1, Reel 10)
- Audio Reel, 1965-06-03, 1965-06-07 (Box 1, Reel 11)
  Gemini 4 flight take off about 10:15am, McDivitt, White - last part of the tape
- Audio Reel, 1965-06-07, 1965-06-10, 1965-06-11 (Box 1, Reel 12)
  Side 1 - Landing of Gemini 4
  Side 2 - Last half - landing from Wasp and boarding plane for Houston, Very last - news conference
- Audio Reel, 1965-06-11, 1966-06-03, 1966-06-06, 1966-09-12 (Box 1, Reel 13)
  Side 1 - News Conference of McDivitt and White
  Side 2 - Launching, Cernan and Stafford, Successful landing of Gemini 9, Gemini 11 - just a few feet left on end
- Audio Reel, Cooper and Conrad Gemini V, 9:00am, 8 day mission, 1965-08-21 (Box 1, Reel 14)
- Audio Reel, 1965-10-25, 1965-12-04, 1965-12-18, 1966-03-26, 1966-05-18 (Box 1, Reel 15)
  Side 1 - Shirra and Stafford did not go, Atlas Agena did not go, Gemini VII Frank Borman - Jim Lovell, Splash down, 9:05am
  Side 2 - News report of Neil Armstrong, David Scott, not all used, Agena - 10:15am lost the bird, Gemini 9 scrubbed for today
- Audio Reel (Box 1, Reel 16)
  Side 1 - Gemini III "Molly Brown", 2-man shot, Grissom, Young
  Side 2 - Splash down, News conference